{
    "id": "4c53d38ebaa843e99f60cd63a3aecaf2",
    "title": "Sequence Of Tenses",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I wanted to know why he …………………….. angry with me.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I will write some letters if I ……………………… time.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the future tense, we use a present tense in the subordinate clause to refer to the future.",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "will have"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "There ……………………… an accident near the bridge.",
            "description": "The present perfect is the most normal tense for giving news of recently finished events.",
            "answers": [
                "has been",
                "was",
                "is"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………. six coffees since morning.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect to say that something has happened several times up to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "drank",
                "had drunk",
                "have drunk"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "What ……………………… you do then?",
            "description": "Then is a past time expression. We do not use the present perfect tense with past time expressions.",
            "answers": [
                "did",
                "have",
                "do"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………………… to Australia?",
            "description": "We use the present perfect when we are thinking of a period of time up to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "Did you ever go",
                "Have you ever been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "They made him ……………………… them everything.",
            "description": "The verb make is followed by object + infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "tell",
                "to tell",
                "telling"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He …………………………… to visit the children once a week.",
            "description": "We use a passive verb here because the subject is not the doer of the action.",
            "answers": [
                "allowed",
                "is allowed",
                "is allowing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She ……………………….. a Greek goddess.",
            "description": "We use the simple present tense to talk about facts.",
            "answers": [
                "resembles",
                "is resembling",
                "resemble"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "It looks as if the sun ………………………… round the earth.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is going",
                "went",
                "goes"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I used to play a lot of tennis when I ……………………….. younger.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "was",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Three more of the missing hikers ………………………….",
            "description": "The present perfect tense is the most normal tense for giving news of recent events.",
            "answers": [
                "has been found",
                "have been found",
                "were found"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}